Sample exam the second file, task number six.
Let's create this class diagram first. This
is the class diagram. And now let's do the
object diagrams. Instance of A. And
it requires a link to an instance of C. We
don't have C yet, but we do have a C here
and the object diagram. So, let's create a
C. Let's call it just c, small C like this.
And we pick it now since it exists. And now,
A requires a link to B. Do we have B? Yes,
we have two Bs. So, let's create one now.
Let's call it "b", just B plain, like this.
And let's pick it so it gets connected. And
now we need another B. So, create a new one,
let's call it b1, just like it's called
here. Let's put it here and pick it. It is
linked. And the software is not complaining
anymore. Let me fix this. So, it looks less
messy. Okay, so now without any intervention
from me, the software, the XModeler will
recognize that A gets connected to two Bs
with association z, which is this one here.
And this is because of the multiplicity. This
multiplicity here. So, the existence of an
A requires the existence of at least two Bs,
and they get connected with this A with z.
This is why we have these two zs here.
And now the last one here that we have this
x. Let's just try to do it. Let's connect
it. So, I'm going to do link, and I'm going
to let XModeler interpret it however it wants.
So, we have from b1 to A, let's do this, okay.
It says we have x and z. So, what happens
if we choose z? The link already exists. So,
this B here gets connected to either no As
at all, or to one A. A is already connected
to an A. Of course, we're talking about association
z. So, you don't connect with z anymore like
this. Now let's do link again, let's go from
B to A. And let's do-, let's choose x this
time. And yes, it is working. So, now according
to the XModeler software, this object diagram
is fine. And it conforms to the first class
diagram, which is this one here. This one,
the upper one. And now we are done with this,
but I'm just going to add another A, and I'm
not going to fulfill the requirements of A,
that A wants to connect to B whatever. I'm
just going to throw in A here, a second instance
of A and I'm going to connect. Let's do this
B. Let's try to connect this B with A using
z. Let's check whether this multiplicity will
prevent us from doing that. So, an instance
of A whatever, call it a1, ignore everything,
just throw it here and link from this B to
this A. Yes, and then these two zs. The multiplicity
does not allow a new link. So, this is exactly
because of this multiplicity. So, this B is
already connected to an A with a z association.
This is why you cannot connect it to another
A with a z association. So yes, this one is
fine. This one is conforming to the first
object diagram-, the first class diagram.
Let me clear this and let's try the second
object diagram. So, we have D now, let's do
a B. Add instance. Call it just plain b. So
far, so good. And then let's do an A. And
now, an A requires a C. Do we have a C? No,
not yet. But do we have a C here in the actual
object diagram? Yes. So, we're fine. Let's
create a C, let's call it just plain c, throw
it in here. And because and now it's connected,
but you cannot see it because a new window
just-, we got a new dialog window. So, the
object requires a link to an instance of B
now. So A, something of type A, or this A
that we just created, requires a B. Do we
have a B? Okay, let's connect it. It's complaining
again. Why? Because the link already exists.
So, this means-. How do I close this? So,
we still have an issue, this means we need
to create another B. Come on.
So, now XModeler is not complaining
anymore. But we have one too many Bs. We
have an extra B that we don't have in the
actual object diagram. This is bad news. Let
me fix this mess. So, this is how it looks
like. If it were to be accepted by XModeler,
if it were-, if it's something that conforms
to this class diagram, but this is of course,
not the object diagram that we have here.
And there's no need to continue with linking
the y here, like doing this, by association,
and this x here. Which is missing here, by
the way; we still don't have it. We need an
x between V and A. There's no need for that.
We are already-, these object diagrams are not
conforming to the class diagram. Let's
do the third one. Let me remove this one.
Let's do C first, let's do an instance of
C like this. Call it c. Everything is fine.
Do an instance of B. Call it b. Put it here.
Do another instance of B. Call it b1, put
it here. And now let's do an instance of A.
Call it "a". Small "a", of course, and put it here.
And now a requires a link of something of
type C. So, you might think, okay, let's link
it with this one here, with this C that we
already have. Well, then you have an object
diagram that's not the same as this one.
Because here, the C is separated. It's not
linked with anything. But if you look here,
you see that every B is also a C because of
this inheritance. So, what you do is you try
to link it with something of type C, which
is what, I mean, something of type B, which
is (in turn) a C. But for some reason, the software,
the XModeler, does not allow us to
choose one of the Bs that we already have
and are covered by this window. It just allows
us to pick this c. So, what I'm going
to do is I'm going to ignore this issue for
a while. It's fine. And I'm going to do a
link like this from A to B and it accepts
x or z. So, let's do, since we have x, z
and we have x, z, let's just do x, whatever,
and click anywhere to refresh. It's linked
and now it says "a" requires a link to a B.
Okay, choose a B. It did not accept it. Since
we already connected some, this is my guess.
But let's do b1 now. So, it's connected. Nothing
wrong here. I mean, the software is not complaining
about anything. So, seems like it just does
not allow you to choose to link with something
of type C that is not explicitly C. So, it
did not show us Bs, these two Bs here,
in spite of them being also C. But when you
do link them, it accepts it, has no problem
with that, it recognizes, well, okay, here we
have an A and this A requires two Bs, at
least. Sorry, we were talking about, yeah, we
talked about this multiplicity. So, this A,
it requires connection x, association x with
something of type C, and yeah. This is something
of type C, and this is the x, everything is
fine. Now, let me fix this mess. Okay, this
is good. Now it looks very similar to this
one here. We can see that the only thing missing
here is a link from B to A with an x. So,
let's do this here. Let's choose x and click
OK. Click anywhere to refresh. And it got
accepted. So, just let me fix the mess again.
And here we are. It is exactly this object
diagram here. So, you can say, we can safely
say the third object diagram conforms to the
first class diagram. Now let's do the second
class diagram. Actually, not yet, because
I forgot, we still have two object diagrams
here, d and e. So, now let's do e. Sorry, d,
the fourth one, an instance of B, call it
b. Put it here, another instance of B, call
it b1, put it here. And an instance of A,
call it "a", put it in the middle. And now it
complains it needs to connect to something
of type B. Why? It is because of this multiplicity
here. So, it's going to require two Bs
actually. Let's link. And now let's link again.
And now it's complaining about a C. So, every
B is already a C. So, first of all, it's requiring
the C because of this multiplicity. So, when
you have an A, and you have, then you have
to have one or two Cs, exactly one or two.
And we know that every B is a C because of
this inheritance. But for some reason, the XModeler
does not just show it here. So, you know
this issue and you link it manually.
You say: give me one of these Bs and link it
to this A, and let's use an x association.
Let's refresh. So, this is fine. But what
is not fine is that this one does not even
look like an object diagram. This is a big problem
here. Let me fix the mess first. Okay, so
this is how it looks like. This link here,
this association between B and A is fine.
It's an x. It's exactly this one here that
we have the object diagram. But we have two
extra zs. And this is because of the multiplicity
here, here. So, when you have an A, you have
to have two Bs at least. This is the—.
You have to have two Bs at least, and of
course, then being connected through z each.
So, this is a problem here. And yeah, let's
try to remove it. It's going to complain again.
It still says it requires a link to an instance
of B at level zero. So, this object diagram
does not fit this class diagram. Let's
do this one now. An instance of B. Call it
b, put it here, no complaints. An instance
of A. Actually, let me do an instance of C first,
put it here. No complaints, and now an instance
of A, call it a, put it here. Now it requires
something of type B. So, yeah, this is the
problem. We have an A, that's requiring two
Bs because of this multiplicity. Two Bs,
and they have to be also connected with the
z association. So, first of all, we don't
have two Bs, we only have one. Second thing
is this B is separated, it's not connected.
There has been no mention of z associations
here at all. So, you can safely say this object
diagram does not conform to the first class
diagram, to this one. And now let's do the
second class diagram. Okay, so this is the
class diagram. This is exactly this one here.
Now let's do the object diagrams. And again,
let's do the first one. Call it "a",
put it here. It requires a C. Why? Because
of this multiplicity here, so it requires
at least one C, and that's most two Cs.
Do we have a C already? No. But do we have
a C here in the object diagram? Yes. So, let's
create a C, call it c, and put it here. And
pick it here and click OK. So, now it's linked.
And it's linked, of course, with an x.
Let's do an instance of B, call it b, put
it here, no complaints, nothing is happening.
Do another B, add an instance of B, call it
b1, put it here, no complaints, everything
is fine. But now we still have to do these
associations. So, let's click link, let's
go from A to B. And it says the selected objects
do not fit any association definition. So,
when you try to connect this A with a B, it
does not connect at all. Let's try again,
it does not work. Why? Because the x here
or the z or any association here does not
link between an A and a B. So, every A is
a B, and every C is a B. So, this is like
a parent and these are the children, these
are the offspring, whatever you want to call
them. So, they are inheriting. So, every A
is a B, every C is a B, and an A can connect
to one or two Cs with an x. A C can connect
to nothing or one A with an x. But nothing
can. There is no connection, there is no
association with a generic B that's not a
specific B of type C or A. And these here are
Bs. These are of this class. So, no matter
what you do, you cannot connect them. There
is nothing to do here. So, you can safely
say this object diagram does not fit this
class diagram. And also, you can notice already
that we don't even have to, you don't even
need to analyze here and think at all. Just
look at the class diagram. You have two associations
x and y. And here you have x and z. So, there
seems to be a mismatch here. Let's do the
second object diagram. Let me clear this.
Let's do an instance of D. Call it d. Okay,
put it here. No requirements, no complaints.
Let's do an instance of B. Put it here. Again,
nothing is happening. Let's do an instance
of A, put it here. And now an A needs to connect
to a C. Do we have a C already? No. We don't
have, but do we have a C in the object diagram?
Yes, we do. So, it's fine. Let's create a C,
let's call it just plain c. And let's put
it here. And let's connect. So, okay, it's
connected now. And it decided to connect with
an x. So, the software, the XModeler recognized
that we connected it with an x. There is not
much of an option here. So, no complaints.
Now, let's try to connect these new links.
A link from D to B. And it recognizes that
it is a y again, there is not much option here.
Let's link B and A. And it says: “It does
not fit any association definition.” So,
it's similar to the previous case here. Again,
we have a generic B, that's not A and not
C, it's just a general B here. And we're trying
to connect it with a specific B which is
an A, and there is no such link. Bs are
not connected to Cs or As. So, there
is no association that fits. This means this
class diagram does not fit, does not conform
to the second class diagram. So, this object
diagram, this one here, does not fit this
one here. Let's do the fourth object diagram,
which is this one. And instead of an instance of
B, call it b1. Put it here. An instance
of B, just call it b, put it here. An instance
of A, call it a, put it here. And now it requires
a link to something of type C. Why? Because
of this multiplicity here. So, an A requires
at least one C. So, we can already say that
we failed, this object diagram does not conform
to this ground. So, let's do the next one. An instance of A, call it "a", put
it here. It requires something of type C,
but this time we have something of type C.
So, let's create one here. Let's call it c,
put it here. Link it and it recognizes that
it connects with an x, which is good for us.
Because we have an x here. Let me fix this
one here. Let me fix the mess. Actually, it's
not going to be much messy because we don't
have that many associations. So, now let's
just create a B. An instance of B. Put it
here. And that's it. Everything is fine. So,
it conforms to the second class diagram.